<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I&#39;m Leslie Myint on Leslie Myint</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi, I&#39;m Leslie Myint on Leslie Myint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prework</title>
      <link>/collection/prework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/prework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Introducing Yourself Online workshop! We look forward to meeting you. Before attending the workshop, please complete the following prework.
Set up RStudio Cloud Sign up for a free RStudio Cloud account at https://rstudio.cloud/ before the workshop. I recommend logging in with an existing Google or GitHub account, if you have one (rather than creating a new account with another password you have to remember). I want you to be able to work from your own laptop in this workshop, but Cloud is an important back-up plan should you run into troubles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;#34;postcards&amp;#34;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS). packageVersion(&amp;#34;postcards&amp;#34;) [1] ‘0.2.0’ Create GitHub repo Online.
Clone GitHub repo usethis::create_from_github(&amp;#34;https://github.com/apreshill/global-postcard.git&amp;#34;) ✨ Commit &amp;amp; Push! ✨</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;#34;blogdoown&amp;#34;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS). packageVersion(&amp;#34;blogdown&amp;#34;) [1] ‘1.0’ Create GitHub repo Online.
Clone GitHub repo usethis::create_from_github(&amp;#34;https://github.com/apreshill/global-blogdown.git&amp;#34;) ✨ Commit &amp;amp; Push! ✨</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS). &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’ Create GitHub repo Online.
Clone GitHub repo usethis::create_from_github(&amp;quot;https://github.com/apreshill/global-distill.git&amp;quot;) ✨ Commit &amp;amp; Push!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description> Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection/day02/03-blogdown/index.md To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection My layout is: single-series part 2! does this work? now for some very cool things more get ready! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The twin brushstrokes of my marriage and career</title>
      <link>/writing/twin-brushstrokes-marriage-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/twin-brushstrokes-marriage-career/</guid>
      <description>I remember the day that I fell in love with teaching. A few weeks into my first graduate school experience as a teaching assistant, I stood in front of a sunlit classroom brushing the chalk off my jeans and looked at my students. No clacks of fingers on keyboards, no eyes glued to screens–just small nods, smiles as understanding finally came. Statistics has a bad reputation for being dry and challenging (&amp;ldquo;You teach statistics?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quest to find invisible giants: the myth of progress</title>
      <link>/writing/invisible-giants-myth-of-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/invisible-giants-myth-of-progress/</guid>
      <description>Sir Isaac Newton once said, &amp;ldquo;If I have seen further, it is by standing on the shoulders of giants.&amp;rdquo; This quote has come to represent the admiration of progress in human knowledge. It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful quote. It inspires: it prompts us to look forward, to yearn to see further. It humbles: it turns our gaze backwards for a moment, to pay homage to the labors granting us these higher vantage points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Lure</title>
      <link>/writing/lightning-lure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/lightning-lure/</guid>
      <description>Whenever my husband and I have a conversation with someone new, my heart races. Is he going to ask it or will I? It&amp;rsquo;s usually him…but how will he ask it? He better time it well and not ask it right off the bat. Otherwise there will be stern words over dinner.
The conversation warms up with talk about hometowns, living in Minnesota, being new parents, the challenges of being first-time homeowners, jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal inference throughout the statistics curriculum</title>
      <link>/talk/2022_08_10_jsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2022_08_10_jsm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A metabolic view of symptoms in kidney disease</title>
      <link>/talk/2022_04_01_stthomas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2022_04_01_stthomas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grading doesn&#39;t have to suck</title>
      <link>/writing/grading-can-be-inspiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/grading-can-be-inspiring/</guid>
      <description>Grading doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to suck—for teachers or for students. Two books on grading have inspired me to adopt a reinvigorated mindset towards grading and feedback: Specifications Grading by Linda Nilson and Grading for Equity by Joe Feldman. In this post, I want to summarize key ideas from both books and share my thought process for course preparation that incorporates the essential parts of both frameworks.
Table of Contents Why change grading systems?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A package for exploring biomedical concept graphs: An alternative to manual literature review</title>
      <link>/talk/2021_08_05_bioc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2021_08_05_bioc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What did I just read?</title>
      <link>/talk/2020_10_30_minne_wiads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2020_10_30_minne_wiads/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphs Galore! Representing Knowledge in the Sciences and Humanities</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_10_22_carleton/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_10_22_carleton/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical methods for querying the regulatory role of DNA</title>
      <link>/talk/2019_03_22_creighton/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019_03_22_creighton/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes A A A A A A A A 6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px) Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dungeons and Dragons Web Scraping with rvest and RSelenium</title>
      <link>/writing/dnd-scraping-rvest-rselenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/dnd-scraping-rvest-rselenium/</guid>
      <description>I love Dungeons and Dragons. I am also a data-loving statistician. At some point, these worlds were bound to collide.
For those unfamiliar with Dungeons and Dragons (DnD), it is a role-playing game that is backed by an extraodinary amount of data. The overall gist is that players create characters that band together with other characters to travel the world and adventure. Essentially, it&amp;rsquo;s collective storytelling aided by dice as vehicles of chance and uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Why</title>
      <link>/writing/book-of-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/book-of-why/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading The Book of Why by Judea Pearl and Dana Mackenzie, and I really enjoyed it. I had been wanting to read it for some time now because I know very little about methodology relating to causal diagrams and structure learning. The book provides an overview of the main ideas that formed and historical events that led up to what Pearl calls the &amp;ldquo;Causal Revolution&amp;rdquo;, a burgeoning of the direct interrogation of causation as opposed to its implicit renouncement in science for a period before then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for using the Hugo academic theme</title>
      <link>/writing/hugo-academic-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/hugo-academic-tips/</guid>
      <description>I recently migrated my personal website and Wordpress blog to blogdown. As an academic, it was natural to use the Academic theme. The blogdown package made the conversion fairly straighforward, but I still had to spend some time figuring out how to work with this Hugo theme.
The source and rendered files for my website are available on GitHub:
Public, rendered site: the public directory within my blogdown/Hugo project Hugo content and source files: all files and directories within my blogdown/Hugo project (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fight every battle everywhere: this is science</title>
      <link>/writing/fight-every-battle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/fight-every-battle/</guid>
      <description>I love Game of Thrones. I particularly liked this mini-speech from Petyr Baelish earlier in Season 7:
Don’t fight in the North or the South. Fight every battle everywhere, always, in your mind. Everyone is your enemy, everyone is your friend. Every possible series of events is happening all at once. Live that way and nothing will surprise you. Everything that happens will be something that you’ve seen before.
As I let my mind wander away from work for a bit today, I realized that this is a wonderful quote about science!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Shiny app with Google login</title>
      <link>/writing/shiny-app-with-google-login/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 18:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/shiny-app-with-google-login/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Shiny application that enables user login can be useful for tailoring individual user experience and for analyzing user actions with profile-type data. With basic file I/O functions, it is possible to create a simple but insecure app that stores login names and passwords in text files. A much more secure alternative is to use an existing authentication system to handle login. I’m sure many of you have seen websites that allow you to login via Google or Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is likelihood?</title>
      <link>/writing/what-is-likelihood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 03:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/what-is-likelihood/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a TA for an introductory biostatistics sequence at JHSPH where we teach students about the essentials of regression analysis. A great question that came up at office hours last week was, “What is likelihood?” I love this question because it is so fundamental to statistical thought, seems very intuitive, but actually abounds in nuance.
I found my answer to the question to be rather unsatisfying: “Likelihood refers to how probable our collected data would be given the regression model that we’re currently fitting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching real math with computers</title>
      <link>/writing/teaching-real-math-with-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 17:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/teaching-real-math-with-computers/</guid>
      <description>As per a friend’s suggestion, I watched Conrad Wolfram’s TED talk on reforming mathematics education. He advocates increased use of computers in the classroom and, in particular, champions the idea of teaching math via programming. There were a lot of ideas both in and missing from his talk that I found interesting to think about.
Mathematics can be taught via programming Mr. Wolfram points to the procedural and algorithmic nature of mathematics to say that a fuller understanding of mathematics can be achieved by having students write programs that implement concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapting education style to improve relevance and practical skills</title>
      <link>/writing/adapting-education-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 17:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/adapting-education-style/</guid>
      <description>Part of my educational duties this past semester was as a teaching assistant for an undergraduate introductory biostatistics course. We went over the usual topics—calculating probabilities from tables, test statistics, hypothesis testing, linear and logistic regression—and I felt that the curriculum made a great effort to contextualize the material by organizing the content into goal-oriented modules. For example, linear regression was introduced as a tool for the specific goal of explaining college students’ GPA based on alcohol consumption-related characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivating the question</title>
      <link>/writing/motivating-the-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 23:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/motivating-the-question/</guid>
      <description>Apathy is the cancer of today’s classroom. Once it plants its nasty little head in a student’s mind, it can be one tough beast to eradicate. Complaints like “I don’t care about this” and “When would I even use this?” are frighteningly common in higher education and indicate a malady far worse than boredom: time wasted. Not only are students wasting time being in class, cranking out hours of work to learn material that won’t be retained or appreciated, but teachers are also wasting their time preparing mechanical, need-agnostic material that will ultimately make no impact on their students’ interaction with the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on the Interactive Mathematics Program</title>
      <link>/writing/imp-perspectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 02:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/imp-perspectives/</guid>
      <description>My pre-college mathematics education was probably different from most others. Instead of adopting the standard approach of teaching Algebra I and II, Geometry, and Trigonometry, my school district took up the Interactive Mathematics Program (IMP), a problem-centric approach to learning the essential material from these subjects. The program was split into 4 courses, each the equivalent of a middle school year or high school semester, and each course was split into approximately 5 units.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why statistics can be scary</title>
      <link>/writing/why-statistics-can-be-scary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 02:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/writing/why-statistics-can-be-scary/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been planning for some time to start this blog mainly as a way to give intuition to people untrained in statistics about what statisticians do and why. For the last few weeks, I’ve been gathering ideas, and I’ve found that in the process I’ve had to be a lot more reflective about fundamental aims in statistics that I had almost started taking for granted. So as a brief aside, I highly encourage people to blog!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Favorite Problems</title>
      <link>/12_favorite_problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/12_favorite_problems/</guid>
      <description>How can I truly reach every student without burning out? How can we make inspiring and successful education available to everyone? How can I be a good mother? How do I raise my daughter to be kind and have a fulfilling life? How do I contribute to a fulfilling marriage for me and my husband? What do I owe the world? What can I do to help safeguard human knowledge?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/</guid>
      <description>Research description.
Research projects
Item 1 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I teach the following courses at Macalester. Some of my courses have course websites which you can navigate to below. For many of my classes I make lecture videos, which can be found on my YouTube channel.
STAT 125: Epidemiology STAT 155: Introduction to Statistical Modeling Class notes in collaboration with Brianna Heggeseth and Kelsey Grinde [S20] STAT 253: Statistical Machine Learning [S19], [S21], [S23] STAT 451: Causal Inference [S20], [F20], [S23] </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
