<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Leslie Myint</title>
    <link>https://lmyint.github.io/categories/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Leslie Myint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 03:13:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://lmyint.github.io/categories/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is likelihood?</title>
      <link>https://lmyint.github.io/post/what-is-likelihood/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 03:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lmyint.github.io/post/what-is-likelihood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently a TA for an introductory biostatistics sequence at JHSPH where we teach students about the essentials of regression analysis. A great question that came up at office hours last week was, “What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; likelihood?” I love this question because it is so fundamental to statistical thought, seems very intuitive, but actually abounds in nuance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found my answer to the question to be rather unsatisfying: “Likelihood refers to how probable our collected data would be given the regression model that we’re currently fitting. The higher the likelihood that Stata reports, the more likely it is that we observe our data under the specified regression model.” Still not seeing the click, I added, “So essentially the higher the likelihood, the better the model is at fitting, at predicting the data. We’re using likelihood here as a means of measuring the predictive power of a regression model.” Some nodding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about this more, and the standard explanation of likelihood as being “under a certain model” is rather confusing. At least phrased in this way. Students are actually quite familiar with this idea in other settings. So if I could go back and answer the question again, I would want the conversation to go something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So what &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; likelihood?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Good question! Let me ask you this: what’s the probability of rolling a one on a six-sided die?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One-sixth…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ah - what if I told you that it was actually 90%?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silence or contemplation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So why did you say one-sixth?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because there’s a single one out of the six sides.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Right - so you assumed a &lt;strong&gt;model&lt;/strong&gt; of a fair die. And using a model for a fair die, each number has a one-sixth chance of being rolled. I assumed a model of an exquisitely crafted loaded die where the chance of getting a one is 90% and the other five numbers is 2% each.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ok…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re getting close to the meat of it! So I have a model in mind, and you have a model in mind…who’s right? The only way to hope to answer this is with data. Say I rolled this hypothetical die and got a 2, 3, 4, 6, and then a 2. What die model do you think is better?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The fair one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Right - why?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There wasn’t even a single one rolled, and your loaded die is supposed to have a 90% chance to roll a one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Excellent! So the &lt;strong&gt;likelihood&lt;/strong&gt; of our data is higher for the fair die than for my loaded die, which is what led you to prefer the fair die model. Specifically you can calculate the likelihood of the data under your fair die model as &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(\left(\frac{1}{6}\right)^5\)&lt;/span&gt;, and I can calculate the likelihood of the data under my loaded die model as &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\((0.02)^5\)&lt;/span&gt;, which is way lower. We can apply the thinking for this scenario analogously to regression! In regression, we are proposing models for the data just like we were in this dice scenario. It’s just that we’re using a different probability model. Specifically, we assume that the outcomes come from a normal distribution and that the mean of the distribution is some linear combination of covariates. Knowing the covariate information for everyone in our data is just like knowing the sequence of die rolls, and knowing the density function for the normal distribution is just like knowing the probabilities for the six sides of the die!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last bit of this would vary depending on the student’s understanding of the assumptions and setup of linear regression, but I like this line of explanation more than my original one for two teaching strategies that it employs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting the student up to be contradicted.&lt;/strong&gt; Arguably lessons are more memorable for students when they are fairly confident in an answer but end up being told otherwise. Here I wanted to make them think intuitively about a common situation but bring to light their unconscious assumptions by bringing in unusual but plausible assumptions of my own. One of the main points of the explanation, the key dependence of likelihood on the model being proposed, hinges on this awareness of the connection between having a model in mind and being able to calculate probabilities. So making this memorable is key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Framing the unfamiliar in the familiar.&lt;/strong&gt; Abstract concepts are often so because students are not accustomed to the language that we instructors are using to describe them. However, by framing the concept in a familiar context, students can more easily make the leap. It’s also a nice way to explain something twice without just repeating yourself twice. Essentially, analogies are the way to go when explaining something complex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching real math with computers</title>
      <link>https://lmyint.github.io/post/teaching-real-math-with-computers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 17:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lmyint.github.io/post/teaching-real-math-with-computers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As per a friend’s suggestion, I watched Conrad Wolfram’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/conrad_wolfram_teaching_kids_real_math_with_computers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TED talk&lt;/a&gt; on reforming mathematics education. He advocates increased use of computers in the classroom and, in particular, champions the idea of teaching math via programming. There were a lot of ideas both in and missing from his talk that I found interesting to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;mathematics-can-be-taught-via-programming&#34;&gt;Mathematics can be taught via programming&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Wolfram points to the procedural and algorithmic nature of mathematics to say that a fuller understanding of mathematics can be achieved by having students write programs that implement concepts. I completely agree that if you truly understand a concept, you can program it, but it’s worthwhile trying to consider how this might actually play out in middle and high school curricula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is useful to think about why this was such an interesting idea to many people in the first place. (It did get a TED talk after all.) The main point is that programming is not something that most people have any real idea of until they try it. I really didn’t understand what programming was about until I took an introductory class in college. I ended up loving it because I enjoyed the thorough and organized type of thinking that it encouraged, and I saw how useful it could be. People who are programmers or use programming regularly, like Mr. Wolfram, are very much convinced of its utility and are naturally excited about introducing this type of thinking earlier on in the education process. There are a few points that came to mind when weighing the pros and cons of a programming-oriented mathematics education:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-can-be-a-great-way-to-reinforce-concepts&#34;&gt;Programming can be a great way to &lt;strong&gt;reinforce&lt;/strong&gt; concepts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember learning how to solve the tower of Hanoi puzzle in the children’s section of museums and in puzzle games long before I saw it again in my freshman year programming class. If placed before me, I probably would have been able to go through the motions from rough recollections or intuition, but the task at hand was to write a program that would solve an arbitrary tower of Hanoi puzzle (i.e. with any number of discs). Suddenly rough intuition needed to be transformed into a precise set of instructions, and it was the fact that I was seeing a familiar problem recast in a more general way that made the exercise relevant and memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With standard pre-college mathematics education, a similar strategy could be adopted. As a specific example, solving systems of two equations with two unknowns is a standard algebra topic that could benefit from programming-type exercises. After students learn the technique of solving these problems, they hone their skills on practice problems and ideally are able to develop intuition on how to solve them by sight. Making this intuition more precise is where a programming exercise could come in. After students gain facility with solving the problems, we have them make their understanding more rigorous by asking them to write a very specific set of instructions to solve any such system of equations. Suddenly they must think about how &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; they choose the scaling numbers for the equations and how they choose to add or subtract the two equations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-is-probably-not-the-best-way-to-introduce-a-topic&#34;&gt;Programming is probably not the best way to &lt;strong&gt;introduce&lt;/strong&gt; a topic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because an activity truly assesses understanding doesn’t mean that it automatically lays the foundation for a lesson plan. If all of my algebra lessons had been formatted as a series of instructions in the way that a programming perspective would emphasize, I know I would have enjoyed my math class a lot less. And I definitely would not have been ready to write a program to solve arbitrary systems of equations the day the topic was introduced. When material is presented as formulaic, as a procedure, students are compelled to simply memorize the steps involved in solving problems. The intuition is removed, and the concepts don’t stick past the next test. I still think that teachers should strive to motivate the material as much as possible—whether that be through telling a story or getting students to see how useful the concept can be. This is important in both a classroom instructional setting and in a homework design setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-features-of-programming-can-be-useful-for-structuring-material&#34;&gt;Some features of programming can be useful for &lt;strong&gt;structuring&lt;/strong&gt; material&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons why people write code is to organize groups of related procedures and perform them in a consistent way in many different occasions. I can see this being useful in a geometry classroom, for example. Students could organize their knowledge of geometrical formulas by having classes containing functions used for computing perimeters, areas, and volumes. Also, the process of writing the actual functions is an exercise in helping students remember precisely what quantities are needed to calculate others. The way that students would end up using these functions is another source of excitement for people who code regularly. Students would use their library of geometry functions to solve more involved problems by creating an organized sequence of function calls to solve each step of the problem in sequence. Programmers love being able to clearly see the overall flow of a complex procedure as a sequence of smaller tasks. Essentially, the function-oriented nature of programming enables students to put &lt;a href=&#34;http://simplystatistics.org/2015/02/04/knowledge-units-the-atoms-of-statistical-education/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;knowledge units&lt;/a&gt; into a documented story-like framework, which hopefully would encourage big picture understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;technology-can-enrich-education-not-dumb-it-down&#34;&gt;Technology can enrich education, not &amp;ldquo;dumb it down&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Mr. Wolfram’s big idea was to use programming to teach math, I think the main subtheme of his talk was the increased incorporation of technology in math classrooms. Not &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.informationweek.com/mobile/ipads-in-the-classroom-worth-doing-right/d/d-id/1110490?&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;technology for technology’s sake&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in terms of gadgets like &lt;a href=&#34;http://theinnovativeeducator.blogspot.com/2010/05/why-smartboards-are-dumb-initiative.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Smartboards&lt;/a&gt; and iPads, but thoughtfully constructed, computer-oriented lesson-plans, assignments, and activities. Technology, when appropriately used, can enrich education, and I think that the main avenue for this is through simulation and exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simulation can be an amazing activity for getting students to think about real-world applications of what they are learning. For example, a lot of the simulations provided on &lt;a href=&#34;http://serc.carleton.edu/sp/library/simulations/examples.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this site&lt;/a&gt; have to do with the very practical task of learning about economics and could quite feasibly fit into an algebra curriculum. Just covered equations of lines? Well how about reinforcing those concepts and showing their utility by exploring linear trends that pop up in economics? If it is not common already, simulations should be more seriously considered by educators as add-on exercises to enhance a curriculum. I find simulations appealing as a teaching tool because they allow students to quickly try lots of things, allowing them to see a wide variety of phenomena in a short span of time. Most importantly, this allows them to &lt;strong&gt;discuss&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;write&lt;/strong&gt; much more just because they have observed so much that they can comment on. Talking, and even more so writing due to its slower and more structured nature, is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED544239.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;great way&lt;/a&gt; to assess the extent to which students understand a topic, and if high quality writing is emphasized, it can really get students to internalize ideas. So in short, technology should be used as a means of facilitating a high volume of &lt;strong&gt;exploration&lt;/strong&gt; so as to facilitate more &lt;strong&gt;writing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;discussion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming can definitely enrich math education by helping students organize concepts and reinforce their understanding of the material. However, we still have to make sure that we motivate material and put it into a memorable context for students. Regarding the broader goal of increasing the presence of technology in education, expensive and ineffective approaches should be abandoned for activities that can be performed on computers and equipment already available in schools. Activities such as simulations can markedly deepen investigation of a topic and are easily performed with the materials available in most classrooms. Amending curricula to incorporate these ideas and activities might involve some time investment, but it could definitely improve the quality of student learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapting education style to improve relevance and practical skills</title>
      <link>https://lmyint.github.io/post/adapting-education-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 17:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lmyint.github.io/post/adapting-education-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Part of my educational duties this past semester was as a teaching assistant for an undergraduate introductory biostatistics course. We went over the usual topics—calculating probabilities from tables, test statistics, hypothesis testing, linear and logistic regression—and I felt that the curriculum made a great effort to contextualize the material by organizing the content into goal-oriented modules. For example, linear regression was introduced as a tool for the specific goal of explaining college students’ GPA based on alcohol consumption-related characteristics. Whether or not the dataset that we gave to the students was the best source of information for investigating this relationship, I felt that there were two pedagogical ideas behind this module that were well implemented. First, the relationship being explored (I would guess) is one that piques the interest of a large percentage of the students. A lot of college students drink and almost everyone knows someone who drinks. It was great that the theme for this module was self-motivating. Second, the structure of the main assignment for the module forced students to write in a substantive way. The students had to come up with their own linear regression models to explore the relationship between GPA and drinking-related characteristics, and they were asked to write a report of their process, findings, and model interpretations—all things that are essential to understand when reading, writing, and discussing research findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to focus on these two teaching ideas for a bit and give my perspective on what we might need to do to adapt education for the future. Current events have precipitated a lot of intense and particularly emotion-backed discussion about racial injustice and inequality in general. From discussions with people much more knowledgeable and well-spoken than I am, I would have to say that perhaps the most essential asset that a lot of people don’t get from their education is an ability to think critically and argue rationally. These are hard things to do, and I think that school is the place to get people to practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve explained in previous posts, case-based learning is a great way to motivate the concepts being taught in class so that students can see their practical uses and therefore remember the ideas for the long-term. In creating examples and giving context to classroom content, we need to think hard about what those examples will be. Perhaps the best way to really engage students and get them to care about what they’re learning is to use the most current issues possible. For example, I think that someone who decided to create a case-based statistics course for the current generation might have a lot of success using both news and research articles about social inequality. I think the key is to relate what is being presented in the news to what research has actually been performed and get students to closely examine the relationship between these sources of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rational argumentation is another skill that is lacking in our generation. Very often we tend to talk to and become friends with like-minded people, and we are not as easily forced to question our views and see fallacies in the bases for our opinions. Forcing conversation in an educational setting is a great way to break that comfort zone because there is such a diversity of opinion. I love that the statistics course that I taught for emphasized writing because it forced students to at least put some words behind what they were learning. Just having those words is several steps above rote calculation and memorization in terms of really embedding meaning and understanding. But the way to truly make the most of those words is to construct them carefully to tell a story, to make a point. Words as a list of facts do little to reinforce understanding. To this end, I think that educators should elevate the role of writing to the level of speech and debate. I see this having great potential in mathematics and statistics classrooms. Throughout a statistics course we teach students about tools and the assumptions behind them that are used to draw conclusions from data. To truly assess their understanding of statistical concepts and to put these concepts in a meaningful context, perhaps one of the key assignments or activities of the course would be to read scientific papers and have a debate. In this way, we can prepare students for the types of discussions that they’ll have throughout their life by helping them recognize reasoning flaws in the arguments of others as well as their own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivating the question</title>
      <link>https://lmyint.github.io/post/motivating-the-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 23:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lmyint.github.io/post/motivating-the-question/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apathy is the cancer of today’s classroom. Once it plants its nasty little head in a student’s mind, it can be one tough beast to eradicate. Complaints like “I don’t care about this” and “When would I even use this?” are frighteningly common in higher education and indicate a malady far worse than boredom: time wasted. Not only are students wasting time being in class, cranking out hours of work to learn material that won’t be retained or appreciated, but teachers are also wasting their time preparing mechanical, need-agnostic material that will ultimately make no impact on their students’ interaction with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one way or another, the point of education is to learn how to live in this world—whether to learn specific skills for a job that will pay for our livelihoods or to learn ideas that shape how we react to the people, laws, and situations around us. And one of the most important ways in which education applies in real life is in being able to recognize when and how different concepts pertain to the situation at hand. Too often in classrooms are we given the punch line before the build-up. As education blogger Dan Meyer &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mrmeyer.com/2014/developing-the-question-needs-improvement/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;puts it&lt;/a&gt;, teachers are too excited to present the concept without spending an adequate enough time &lt;em&gt;motivating&lt;/em&gt; the question behind the concept. And the result is a lack of internalization of ideas, a failure to understand why the material being taught is relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I explained in my &lt;a href=&#34;../imp-perspectives&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, the Interactive Mathematics Program (IMP) puts in an admirable effort to motivate the need for mathematical concepts. It presents a tough multi-faceted problem at the beginning of each unit and develops the need for various math topics as it pertains to this overarching problem. I felt that one of the most memorable and instructive units was one in which we attempted to solve the unit problem on the very first day without any formal tools whatsoever. The best part (though frustrating at the time for me) was that this was &lt;em&gt;really hard&lt;/em&gt;. There is definitely something that can be said for having students try to do things inefficiently to learn the &lt;em&gt;merits&lt;/em&gt; of the concepts that teachers are so excited to get to. Or in Dan’s words, there is definitely something that can be said for &amp;ldquo;being less helpful&amp;rdquo;—not jumping straight to teaching students about power tools but momentarily convincing them that the logs on their desks can only be cut with butter knives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introductory statistics courses can definitely benefit from a more problem-oriented and &amp;ldquo;less helpful&amp;rdquo; mentality. For one, I think there is a deluge of formulae for students to learn, and most of the time, the reasons for using them were never really developed or lost in the memorization process. The topic of confidence intervals serves as a great example here. We drill into students’ minds that the formula for a confidence interval is an estimate plus or minus some multiple of the standard error. And we can tell them that the interval gives us a range of possible values for the true population mean. But why are these possible values good ones? Why do we even have to give a confidence interval? Why isn’t it enough to just say that the mean is &lt;em&gt;around&lt;/em&gt; 5, say? When do I ever see confidence intervals in real life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better way to teach this idea than to present a formula and give a two-minute interpretation is to make students see how the idea of a confidence interval is one they are exposed to frequently but in disguise. One way to do this is to present the students with common types of advertisement tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://images.teamsugar.com/files/upl2/1/15259/20_2009/ce49a981caec0edd_cheerios.preview.jpg&#34; width=550&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.popsugar.com/food/FDA-Packaged-Foods-Health-Claims-Make-Them-Drugs-3147756&#34;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lesliemyint.files.wordpress.com/2014/10/c7ae7-colgate.jpg&#34; width=550&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bitedowndeals.com/blog/category/preventive-dentistry&#34;&gt;Image credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statistics presented on these ads are instinctively somewhat convincing. Hey a 4% reduction in cholesterol is pretty good. Wow, 90% of doctors recommend this product! These are definitely worth buying! But we can also think about what numbers on these ads would make us less convinced of the products&amp;rsquo; worth. A cholesterol reduction of 0 to 1% would definitely not make me want to buy Cheerios. And I would be much less impressed by this Colgate toothpaste if 50% or less of doctors recommended it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we give the students data—several sets of data that support or fail to substantiate the Cheerios claim to varying degrees—and ask them to make their own conclusions based on this data. I would expect many of them to take the average lowering of cholesterol as a summary measure; some might look at the median or mode; some might look at the percentage of people who had their cholesterol lowered by some minimal percentage level. No matter how they choose to look at the data the key idea is that the students see how their chosen summary measure(s) vary from dataset to dataset. Sometimes the claims in the ad are supported, and other times they are definitely not. It’s just that companies often only report their summary measures and not how much that measure would vary had they tested their product on different groups of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this point, I think that students would be a little more ready to learn about confidence intervals because they have seen how advertisements, something they encounter all the time, can use (or really conceal) them in misleading ways. And no one likes being duped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is by far not the best way of motivating confidence intervals, but it is a lot more than can be said for the majority of introductory statistics classes. Just taking a little bit more time to think about the everyday applications of statistics can go a long way in making lessons less formulaic and more engaging, and this is something that the statistics community should strive for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspectives on the Interactive Mathematics Program</title>
      <link>https://lmyint.github.io/post/imp-perspectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 02:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lmyint.github.io/post/imp-perspectives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My pre-college mathematics education was probably different from most others. Instead of adopting the standard approach of teaching Algebra I and II, Geometry, and Trigonometry, my school district took up the Interactive Mathematics Program (IMP), a problem-centric approach to learning the essential material from these subjects. The program was split into 4 courses, each the equivalent of a middle school year or high school semester, and each course was split into approximately 5 units. Each unit introduced a mathematically-oriented story, which gave rise to a guiding question that we sought to be able to answer over the course of the unit. For example, in the second year unit “Cookies”, we are introduced to the Woo’s, a family of bakers who wish to optimize their cookie baking choices to maximize their profits. The challenge though is that they have several constraints on their available ingredients and sales capabilities. Over the course of the unit, we learned several ideas related to systems of equations and inequalities that helped us answer this question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I didn’t appreciate it at the time, IMP was attempting to do something that is rarely seen in education these days but is extremely important: motivating the concepts. At the beginning of the “Cookies” unit, I remember that class immediately started off with an attempt to solve the unit problem—no instruction on the best mathematical techniques, just a lot of pain, backtracking, and guesswork. I remember being overwhelmed just after organizing the information provided on the family’s ingredient and sales constraints. And guessing potential solutions was memorably laborious: does it work to make 100 chocolate chip and 170 oatmeal raisin? Rats! That violates constraint 4! What about 150 oatmeal raisin? Nice! That’s allowed! Aw shoot, that makes less money than my 150 chocolate chip, 130 oatmeal raisin combo! Fifty minutes of this and I was pulling my hair out. There must be an easier way to do this! And there was! Which we came to learn over the course of the next month or so that we spent on the unit. This particular unit sticks out in my memory primarily because it did such a good job at motivating the need for the main mathematical tools that we were learning during the unit. Had I taken a standard algebra course, I know I would not have truly internalized the utility of what we learned during that unit. For the most part, IMP did a decent job at contextualizing math concepts, and I think that this is a quality that is lacking in higher education in general. In designing curricula, we are not doing enough to motivate the content of the course, and I plan to explore this idea much further in a future post relating to introductory statistics curricula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of IMP that is particularly well suited to higher education is its emphasis on summarizing and organizing knowledge gained over the course of a unit. At the end of every unit, students are required to create a portfolio of reflections, class notes, and assignments that were instrumental in their comprehension of the main topics. So for example, in my “Cookies” portfolio, I included the first day of class activity that had us take a stab at the unit problem. I also included my class notes on feasible regions and solving systems of linear inequalities. I also wrote a cover letter summarizing the goals of the unit, what I learned from the assignments that I included in the portfolio, and my impressions of how these concepts were useful in everyday life. Portfolio time was always a laborious and dreadful experience for me during middle and high school, but I recognize now how useful a practice it is for being serious about retaining knowledge. As a graduate student, I have been exposed to several fundamental concepts time and time again in different courses, and I have found myself consciously wishing that I had put together portfolios for many of the classes that I took during college. Not only is the act of putting together a portfolio an invaluable synthesis activity, but the portfolio also serves as a one-of-a-kind reference manual. Because it is a collection of notes, homeworks, etc. created, curated, and edited by you, it can be infinitely more readable then a textbook. If you want it to, it can contain all of the steps in the proofs of key theorems, all of the exhaustive explanation that you worked through on your own, all of the fine details that finally made a concept click. A portfolio is a mini-textbook written in the language of your mind and can thus potentially serve as a reference for a very long time. It is a wonderful idea for IMP to introduce this concept to younger students, and I feel that it would be very useful for many high school and college classes to adopt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So essentially the Interactive Mathematics Program, though by no means flawless, takes steps beyond traditional education practices that definitely have merit. Its case-based structuring of learning and its emphasis on creating concept portfolios can really impact the depth of learning and are ideas that nearly all higher education courses can benefit from.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>